[INTRO]
Is your mix a mess?
Sync is drifting. Ducking is pumping.
The alignment looks right but feels wrong.
And the silence? Gutted.
Fix it, or your audience clicks away.
[HOOK]
I am sick of watching creators skip the QA phase.
You stack your plugins, export, and pray.
Praying is not a mixing strategy.
You must test *every single fix* before it goes out the door.
[BODY]
Start with Sync. The cardinal sin.
If the lips don’t match, the brain disconnects.
I don’t care how good the content is. Sync errors signal incompetence.
Match your transients. Zoom in. Be ruthless.
Don’t trust the auto button. Trust the clap test.
If the transient doesn’t land exactly on the spike, you aren’t done.
[EXAMPLE]
Let me give you the specific case that usually bites people.
You used an “AI Alignment” tool.
It snapped every word into a perfect grid.
Looks amazing on the timeline.
Sounds like a lobotomy.
The tool synced the spelling, but it broke the performance.
Cross talk vanished. Laughter chugs.
Test the *feeling* of the alignment, not just the waveform.
[BODY2]
Ducking. The volume villain.
Stop smashing your background music into the dirt.
Sidechain compression is a scalpel, not a hammer.
You want the music to *welcome* the voice, not cower from it.
If the mix sounds like it’s gasping for air every time someone speaks, you ducked too hard.
Test the release time. Fast release sounds nervous. Slow release sounds natural.
Dial in 2 to 4dB. Not 20.
[BODY3]
Silence removal. My biggest pet peeve.
Stripping silence is crucial for pacing.
But “no pause files” kill texture.
If you gut every micro-pause, you sound like a robot reading terms of service.
Your listener needs to breathe.
Test the gaps. Can you hear the room drop out?
If the cut is too tight, the mix sounds like a bad Zoom call.
Leave the grunge. Keep the human space.
[OUTRO]
Here is the takeaway.
Testing these four pillars — Sync, Ducking, Alignment, Silence —
This is what separates the amateurs from the pros.
It’s the difference between “I can hear the audio” and “I can *feel* the mix.”
Don’t ship without the test run.
[CTA]
So I want to know.
Are you Team “Perfect Grid” or Team “Human Feel”?
Do you strip all silence or leave it messy?
Comment below. I’m ready to argue.
Subscribe if you want to win the audio war.
Peace out.