[INTRO]
You open the laptop.
The screen glows.
Pure logic. Clean. Instant.
You write five lines of code.
It works perfectly on the first try.
You feel like a wizard.
Then you close the laptop and reach for the iron.
The spell breaks.
[HOOK]
Everyone thinks you hate soldering because you burn your thumb.
Or the joint is cold.
Or the pad lifts.
No.
You hate it existentially.
Code exists in a Platonic realm of ideas.
Soldering is a negotiation with raw, sweating, awkward physics.
It reminds you that making is not just thinking.
It is a fight.
[BODY]
That fight is the source of the hate.
In software, every mistake is a thought you can take back.
Ctrl+Z. Instant grace.
In hardware, the solder wicks where it wants.
The flux spits.
The joint solidifies.
You look at it and know: this is permanent now.
That permanence is the anxiety.
The fear of the irreversible is what you actually smell when the smoke hits the air.
[EXAMPLE]
I built a split keyboard.
The layout code was a symphony.
Perfect layers. Perfect combos.
The PCBs arrived. Thin. Green. Fragile.