[INTRO]
I sat down to write a test.
Just one.
For a function called `generate_script` in `main.py`.
That’s the deep end of the pool.
How hard can it be?
[HOOK]
Three hours later, I wasn't testing `generate_script` anymore.
I was debugging the *test itself*.
We have all been there. You aren't validating logic.
You are fighting the ghost of your own Python environment.
This is the story of the time I lost an afternoon to a single import statement.
[BODY]
The function looks innocent.
It takes data. Loads a template. Spits out a script.
But `main.py` lives at the root of your app.
It assumes it is the center of the universe.
It imports `config`. It uses relative paths.
When you run it from the terminal? Flawless.
When `pytest` picks it up from the `tests/` directory? Nuclear meltdown.
[EXAMPLE]
Here is the exact test I wrote first.
```python
from main import generate_script
def test_generate():
result = generate_script()
assert "script" in result
```
Looks clean, right?
Run it.
`ModuleNotFoundError: No module named 'config'`.
The code can't find its own skeleton.
Why? Because `main.py` imports using a path that only works when `main.py` is the entry point.
My first hour was fighting `sys.path`. Setting `PYTHONPATH`.
You know the drill. `pathlib.Path(__file__).parent.parent`.
You aren't fixing the code. You are hacking the interpreter just to let the file load.
[BODY2]
I fix the path. I run the test again.
Now it crashes on file I/O.
`generate_script` tries to open a Jinja template.
`open("templates/script.j2")`.
Guess what? When the CWD is `tests/`, that file doesn't exist.
So now I am not testing the logic.
I am mocking the `open` call. I am creating fixtures for the file system.
Opinion? This is the single biggest productivity killer in modern development.
The gap between "the code works" and "the test passes" is a chasm of environmental assumptions.
[BODY3]
Eventually, I gave in.
I rewrote the function to take the template as an explicit parameter.
I injected the config using a fixture.
The test became simple again.
`generate_script(data, template_string, config_obj)`.
Was the refactor painful? Yes.
Did the test force me to write better code? Absolutely.
Debugging the test showed me exactly how brittle my original `main.py` was.
The bug wasn't in `generate_script`. The bug was in how tightly coupled the function was to the world around it.
[OUTRO]
So next time