[INTRO]
The internet is a paradox.
Always connected, yet deeply lonely.
You find a killer video.
The first instinct is to share it.
But sharing a link is a dead end.
You want to watch *at the same time*.
Rtwatch is the answer.
Built on WebRTC.
Peer-to-peer viewing that actually works.
[HOOK]
I am extremely picky about my tools.
If an app asks for my email, I close the tab.
If it wants a login, I block the site.
Rtwatch passes the vibe check instantly.
No signup. No tracking.
Just a link and a promise.
The promise is simple: You and your friend see the exact same frame at the exact same time.
It delivers on that promise flawlessly.
[BODY]
The secret is WebRTC.
Real-time communication between browsers.
It cuts out the corporate middleman completely.
When you press pause, a signal goes *directly* to your friend's browser.
No server handshake. No database write. No polling every three seconds.
Just pure, low-latency action.
It makes the experience feel intimate.
Like you are passing the remote control on a real couch.
This is how technology should feel. Immediate.
[EXAMPLE]
Paint this picture.
Friday night.
Your buddy is in Berlin. You're in Austin.
You want to watch a terrible 90s action movie on a random streaming site.
You pull up Rtwatch.
You drop the direct link to the video.
That is it.
The interface is brutally simple.
You send the generated link to your friend.
They open it.
Boom. Synced perfectly.
No "Can you hear me?" No "Is it playing for you?"
Just shared cultural chaos in real-time.
[BODY2]
Why doesn't every app do this?
Because big platforms don't want you to have direct connections.
They want you in their walled garden.
They want to serve you ads.
They want to data mine your chat history.
Rtwatch is a political statement disguised as a simple utility.
It says the internet belongs to the users again.
It prioritizes human connection over the corporate bottom line.
That radical subtraction is exactly why I love it.
[BODY3]
For the developers watching.
Look at this project.
It is a masterclass in restraint.
Solve one problem perfectly.
Respect the user's privacy obsessively.
Use the right tool for the job.
WebRTC is notoriously tricky.
NAT traversal is a nightmare.
Rtwatch handles the complexity so you don't have to