Most people aren’t testing their models.
They are vibing them.
That isn’t engineering, it’s hoping.
You need a full two-model test via produce.
Vibe checks are a dead man walking.
You can’t ship a product on “feels good.”
A two-model test is a duel.
Your production data is the referee.
This isn’t a cherry-picked demo.
You take the incumbent model and the challenger.
You fire the exact same prompts at both.
Then you judge the outputs.
Say you run an e-commerce bot.
Model A is cheap and fast.
Model B is expensive and smart.
You grab 500 real refund tickets from prod.
You don’t guess which is better. You score them.
Hallucinations. Tone. Resolution rate.
The winner shows up instantly.
“Via produce” is the non-negotiable part.
Synthetic data is a sterile lab.
Your users are a mosh pit.
Test the models in the mosh pit.
If they survive production, they survive anything.
This eliminates the debate.
“I like Model A better.”
Who cares?
The data on your actual user distribution doesn’t lie.
Vibes are subjective. Prod data is objective.
Stop guessing.
Stop trusting the hype cycle.
A full two-model test on your own produce is the only way to ship faster.
Grab your production logs today.
Run the eval. Let the data win.